<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="utgs.xsl" type="text/xsl" version="1.0"?>

<document>
    <title>UTGS - Library of Libraries</title>
    <sub-title>All Documentation</sub-title>

    <chapters>
        <toc>
            <link>
                <title><i>Useless</i> - Library Overview</title>
                <href>UselessOverview.xml</href>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title><i>KooLiXP</i> - Language Overview</title>
                <href>KooLiXPOverview.xml</href>
            </link>
            <link>
                <title><i>KooLiXP</i> - Language Reference Manual</title>
                <href>KooLiXPCompiler.xml</href>
            </link>
        </toc>
        <chapter>
            <title>Preface</title>
            <name>Preface</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    <image src="koolas.png"/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Hi. I am Sadhbh Code, M.Sc. of Computer Science.
                    I've been Lead Programer involved in sevral commercial game projects, for 5 years.
                    The work presented here is derived from these projects.
                    The components of this library were used commercialy in a wide variety of game types,
                    such as: tycoon management, 3rd person advanture, or pack of mini-games for kids.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>On 11-th May 2005</b>, I got the <b>clerical permission</b>, signed by my boss, to place these components into <b>public domain</b>.
                    After then, I was looking for free <i>Subversion</i> host server.
                    If you have access to this project, it means I have found one <code lang="text">;-)</code>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Project Components:
                    <ul>
                        <li><n>Useless</n><d>utility &amp; multimedia library.</d></li>
                        <li><n>KooLib</n><d>utility &amp; KooLiXP library.</d></li>
                        <li><n>Dynamo</n><d>dynamic module loading w/ KooLiXP bound.</d></li>
                        <li><n>strmbase</n><d>public Microsoft Direct Show base classes.</d></li>
                        <li><n>KooLiXP</n><d>executable program linked against all libraries.</d></li>
                        <li><n>vc7.0</n><d>Microsoft Visual C++ 7.0 projects.</d></li>
                        <li><n>vc7.1</n><d>Microsoft Visual C++ 7.1 projects.</d></li>
                        <li><n>gcc</n><d>gcc build &amp; clean scripts.</d></li>
                        <li><n>examples</n><d>examples of usage.</d></li>
                        <li><n>www</n><d>This documentation.</d></li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Virtues:
                    <ll>
                        <li> BSD License,</li>
                        <li> X-platform project via multiple layers of abstraction,</li>
                        <li> Scripting language, easy to learn, with many bindings to components of the library,</li>
                        <li> Extensible thru external modules loaded at run-time,</li>
                        <li> Tested against comercial game projects,</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Features:
                    <ll>
                        <li> Encryption Capable Virtual Filesystem,</li>
                        <li> GUI User Interface Library,</li>
                        <li> XML Resource Library,</li>
                        <li> C++ Utility Templates such as functors, signals, associative containers,</li>
                        <li> DirectShow streaming thru OpenGL textures synchronized with GUI rendering,</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>About <i>KooLiXP</i> Language</title>
            <name>AbountKooLiXP</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    The <i>KooLiXP</i> language is functional like LISP, and object oriented like Python.
                    It looks similar to XSL Transform language, since an XML syntax have been choosed as its form.
                    This is high-level language, where you don't bother how to do a thing, you'd rather think what
                    thing is to be done. It is is realy easy to learn declarative language.
                </p>
                <p>
                    The major features of <i>KooLiXP</i> are:
                    <ll>
                        <li>built-in, <b>just-in-time compiler</b>, which provides ability to create compiled functions from selected parts of code,</li>
                        <li>function <b>currying</b>, which provides ability to in-place creation of function objects with bound selected function and given parameters,</li>
                        <li>infinite <b>streams</b>, when you create listnode with a listnode generator function in a <q>tail</q>,</li>
                        <li>built-in operations such as: <b><i>map</i>, <i>fold</i>, <i>zip</i>, <i>range</i>, <i>seek</i>, <i>head</i></b> providing
                            easy and fast iteration algorithms,</li>
                        <li><b>runtime in-place objects</b>, when you create an object and initial values of its members without having defined any class,</li>
                        <li>import built-in library <b>bindings</b>,</li>
                        <li>control over <b>loading at runtime</b> of user supplied dynamic libraries (win32 DLL or linux SO). </li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See Language Overview...</title>
                        <href>KooLiXPOverview.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See Language Reference Manual...</title>
                        <href>KooLiXPCompiler.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See Complex Example ...</title>
                        <href>KooLiXPComplexExample.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>About <i>Useless</i> Library</title>
            <name>AboutUseless</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    <i>Useless</i> is a library providing solutions usefull in many aspects of creating a game.
                    It introduces abstract <i>File</i>, <i>Image</i>, <i>Sound</i>, <i>Movie</i> and <i>GUI</i> components.
                </p>
                <p>
                    There can be seen few layers in <i>Useless</i> module:
                    <ll>
                        <li>System Interface - provides system windows and events translation to window-level signals,</li>
                        <li>Hardware Abstraction - hardware acceleration for graphics, sound and other multimedia,</li>
                        <li>Images Abstraction - mechanisms to load pixmaps from files onto hardware surfaces,</li>
                        <li>Sounds Abstraction - mechanisms to load samples from files into hardware buffers,</li>
                        <li>GUI - Graphical User Interface - widgets, skins and fonts,</li>
                        <li>XML Resources - creation of items from other layers, based on scipts.</li>
                    </ll>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <link>
                        <title>See Library Overview...</title>
                        <href>UselessOverview.xml</href>
                    </link>
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Thanx</title>
            <name>Thanx</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    I'd like to send big thanx to my boss, who gave me a legal right to place all this stuff into a public domain.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I'd also like to thank my good colegue from company, with whom I've discussed several library topics.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Big thanx for all those people who have beta-tested this software in many projects.
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Finale</title>
            <name>Finale</name>
            <body>
                <p>
                    Use this library for whatever you want.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I'd like to know if you like this project, what good or bad things you see, what would you have changed.
                    I'd like to know if it is usefull or useless in your opinion.
                </p>
                <p>
                    I would be pleased if you don't forget to send me a note to https://github.com/sadhbh-c0d3.
                </p>
            </body>
        </chapter>
    </chapters>

</document>
